Alex McDaniel

JAVASCRIPT WEB DEVELOPER

amcdaniel186@gmail.com
941-387-6863
https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexamcdaniel
https://github.com/amcdaniel86
Miami. FL

Summary

I have over eight years of experience in the sales and customer service industry working for Apple, American Express, Uber and Instacart in South Florida. However, my passion for technology and problem solving led me to study computer science and web development.

I embrace the notion of updating my skills with the ever evolving world of technology and software. I am currently working on my web developer skills using the JavaScript MERN stack.

Education

Web Development

Ironhack 2018 - 2019

Ironhack is an immersive bootcamp with locations in Madrid, Barcelona, and Miami, offering 9-week courses in Full Stack Web Development. (600+ hours)

Technologies: JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Express, MongoDB, HTML, CSS and Bootstrap.

Associate of Arts Engineering

Miami Dade College 2014 - 2017

GPA: 3.5

Political Science

University California Santa Barbara 2008 – 2011

Projects

MusicTopia Music Database

https://musictopia.herokuapp.com/login

Nov 2018 - Dec 2018

A music "wikipedia-esque" CRUD database where registered users are able to modify items in the database.

Technologies Used: JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, Heroku

Ghost Attack

https://amcdaniel86.github.io/My-First-Game/

Oct 2018 - Nov 2018

A simple shooter game, where two players can go up against each other and engage in ghost combat.
Technologies Used: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Canvas

Audiofy Playlist Creator

https://github.com/amcdaniel86

Dec 2018 - In Progress

React application that allows users to create, modify and delete Playlists and Albumlists to create their own personal music library.

Technologies Used: React.js, Node.js, JavaScript, Express.js, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, Heroku

Technical Skills

JavaScript, React.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Node.js, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, Git, GitHub

Experience

Amazon

Independent Contractor Driver/Logistician

Mar 2015 – Current Miami/Fort Lauderdale Area

- As an independent contractor, worked for several technology companies Uber, Amazon, Lyft, Instacart, Postmates and Doordash. I was responsible for managing my own expenses and taxes using Excel and Google Sheets, ensuring I tracked my expenses and revenues accurately.
- Maintained high 4.9 out of 5 stars ratings on thousands of deliveries and rideshare rides.
- Accomplished driver and delivery procurement expert, managing time management, products and the customer experience.

American Express Platinum Customer Care Professional

Nov 2012 - October 2013 Ft. Lauderdale, FL

- In one month sold an additional \$1,200 in products to platinum customers, proactively offering products while still maintaining an excellent service standard.
- Maximized potential by offering relevant offers to members such as other card products and flexible payment options.
- Handled back to back calls usually with no intermission, with excellence and high efficiency as standards, held accountable through time tracking and customer surveys

Apple Specialist/Mentor

Aug 2010 - Feb 2012 Palm Beach Gardens, FL

- Top business networking specialist amassed over 70 business meetups in one month
- Involved in the Mentor and Data Transfer teams, aiding new Mac customers transferring information to their new computers and the mentoring of specialists on the retail floor
- Within top five specialists in the store with 75% attachment rate promoting additional products such as AppleCare and One to One services